Let's
go through
your what your specific roles are, what
areas you're responsible for, where
there's overlap, that sort of thing.
Could you each go through those?
I would say go for it, Roger. Overlap in
all areas. We all work together
on the pro and college side.
So,
you're all doing this I mean,
how do you divvy it up?
We have a ton of collaboration. We watch
all the players together or individually
and then together as a group.
It's not like a college scout where you
divide it up by areas. It's like a pro
scout where you divide it up by teams.
But, all of us are watching pretty much
everyone on the board and in free agency
together.
How did you guys How often do you guys
get together
like during the whole draft process?
Daily.
Daily. Yeah, so we kind of have an an
executive team, a personnel executive
team, and we all kind of work together
for all things, so.
And I don't know who to address this to,
but like when you get a new defensive
coordinator like Raheem Morris coming
in,
how do you go about identifying the
traits
that he wants to, you know, for you guys
to line up in the draft?
>> Yeah, great question. Raheem was
awesome.
He came in and sat down with all of us
and went through each position on
defense, player profiles,
prototypes,
varying levels like starting guy
starting caliber players, backup caliber
players, just talked us through his
whole scheme, watched film with us. So,
he was awesome.
You know, we went through for over an
hour with him when he first got here and
just explained the whole scheme and
it really is very similar to what we've
done in the past. There's some small
tweaks here and there and
gives us some versatility, but that's
how we went about that process. Was that
Romello height type of player that, you
know, 250-lb
outside guy? Was that something that
Raheem kind of highlighted when he first
got here that this is a guy I'd like to
add to the
We started evaluating in the fall. So,
we have him on the board before Raheem
got here.
He's someone that we identified as being
one of the premier pass rushers in this
class.
So, even before
we heard his vision
for Romello, who was a guy that we were
on board with as a successful pass
rusher. It is a player archetype that
we've used in the past like with Dee
Ford,
the DPR kind of guys, so it it's not
something that
unfamiliar with.
Uh, specific things that made Stripling
a gold helmet?
Uh,
I mean, gold helmet is everything and he
checked all those boxes.
Um, he's kind of a unique guy that when
he transferred in,
I'm not certain if Old Miss knew the
quality, the caliber of person and
player that they had early on.
Um,
our scouts loved him right away, our
coaches loved him right away.
Um,
leadership,
goal-oriented, the passion the guy has,
the work ethic, the toughness, the
durability. He checks all those boxes at
a really high level. Standard that he
set for the position room in Old Miss,
it was it was throughout the process.
Our scouts did a great job of getting
more and more information on him,
talking to sources, talking to
teammates, and the more people we talked
to, sources, teammates, the more his
name come came up as the guy who set the
standard and held people accountable and
raised the bar.
The cool thing about Strip, too, is
all the all the traits that we're
talking about, they show up on tape. The
way he blocks, the way he catches the
ball, how unselfish of a teammate he is,
it shows up on tape. So,
all the factors that make you a gold
helmet, they have to show up on tape and
they do for him.
How do you guys determine Josh who you
bring in for 30 visits and
you know, what's the level of
you know, I don't
I can't really state secrets here, but
like, you know,
how do you
smoke screen general, you know,
interest, just stuff you need to know?
Like, how does that process work? Yeah,
it's so interesting because the term top
30 is not something that we use
internally. It's it's 30 visits. It's
not necessarily your top 30 prospects,
but
it's a variation of it could be
character related. It could be guys that
we're trying to recruit as free agents.
It could be guys we just want better
feel for at the top of the draft. So,
it varies for different reasons. There's
no specific, hey, we got to have this
this amount of guys for for this reason
or that. But, we that's one of the
things that we talked about that you
asked earlier about whether we meet, we
we come up with this collaboratively.
So,
How many guys did we bring in this year
that we drafted?
What was that? How many guys did we
bring in this year that we drafted? One,
right? Yeah.
The interesting thing is sometimes we'll
invite these guys before the combine, so
before the coaches ever get to meet them
and then we can invite them all the way
leading up to the actual 30 visit.
So, there's a large span of time where
we invite these guys.
One more? Are there ever ever any um
big disagreements or are
are your traits that you're looking for
so similar that there's not a lot of
that? I mean, I got to imagine once in a
while somebody's I don't I don't buy
this at all, not this guy. I mean, what
Is there ever any of I think RJ and I
had a few healthy disagreements today.
Yeah, some good ones.
>> they're always good conversations and
you know, there's a ton of respect for
each other and we get to the reason why
we disagree and we come to a a decision.
Normally, it's a consensus decision when
everyone gets to add their input and
state their reasons why they believe
what they believe.
The fact is what about Black? Was you
guys surprised he wasn't invited to the
combine and was there some hidden value
because he didn't catch the ball a lot
last year?
Yeah, I think we were very surprised
that he wasn't invited to the combine.
We
since watching his film early in the
fall, we thought he he was a really good
running back, really good player and um
Indiana, their scheme, they they heavily
ran the ball and ran it really well. So,
it's kind of one of those things. It's
not always about what is the player
being asked to do, but what can he do?
And
so, I think throughout the process we
became more and more comfortable with
his pass game ability.
So, excited when he doesn't get invited
to the combine because he's already on
your radar, so less people maybe see
him?
It
It can go both ways because
like if the player pops, a lot of
coaches might go to their pro day and if
their pro day is late, it can be he can
be a late riser or whatnot. So, it's it
really is a balance.
I don't know how busy you guys are, but
is it possible to just go through all
the picks today and just give us kind of
bullet points or what stood out?
Do you have enough time to do that? We
got these picks. It'll be quick. Well,
no, four. You already We've already
talked about three of them. The one we
missed? What's that? Yeah, five today.
We have five today, right?
Um, what what kind of stood out to you
about I'm sorry, who'd you say? Um,
Holton Grayson. Yeah.
Um,
loved the way he got on the field. I'm
sure John said he played on the the
offensive side of the ball. Um,
very very effective attacking, very
effective getting on edges, productive
getting at the ball, has three-down pass
rush value, has three-down value rushing
the passer. Um,
you know, one of the big things that we
saw you was based upon the size, how do
we hold up against double teams? We were
really happy with his anchor and his
overall power.
What about Price Lock?
Price Lock is awesome because he's got
such size and length and for a bigger
guy, he moves like a guy who's smaller.
But, he's a tough competitor. He's a guy
that fits us and he's going to play on
the outside. He's going to compete, so
we like him.
Jaden Docker seems like you know,
different type of linebacker, potential
safety, outside rusher. Where do you
guys see him fitting in? He's really
cool cuz if you go back two years at
Georgia Tech, I'm sorry, at Georgetown,
you know, he's playing safety and then
last year
at Lafayette, he's playing essentially
outside linebacker, setting edges and
then this year he's playing stack
backer. He's a tremendous athlete.
We see him as a linebacker. We don't see
him as
an outside linebacker
on the ball line of scrimmage outside
linebacker.
But, a really talented, gifted,
versatile athlete with as you can tell
by his combine measure or as you can
tell by his measurements, he's
you know, one of the more physically
gifted people.
What about the two offensive lineman,
Willis and Enrique Cruz? Yeah, cover
Willis. He was he was a fun study. You
know, played college tackle in college
and has tackle ability, but we see him
more on the inside and with the scheme
in Washington, we really got to see him
do a lot of what we're going to ask him
to do in terms of the run game,
running off the ball, outside zone and
then with the his pass pro ability at
tackle, sliding inside, we think he can
do really beneficial there and be really
good in pass pro. So, both run and pass,
he checked the boxes. And then with
with Enrique Cruz, he's got he's got a
lot of traits in his body.
He's got really good size, really good
testing numbers and we really like the
film. He he played some good rushers
this year and held his own.
So, in terms of just having a
being able to pick up some extra picks
and being able to add him, we're really
excited about. So, a quick question
about Holton. He's a part-time starter
the last couple seasons at Oklahoma. He
had to make that transition early from
the end to D-tackle.
When there are limited snaps in that
sense, does it offer a challenge in in
of your work evaluating him.
Yeah, I think he can.
Um
everybody kind of has their own
developmental timeline, but we saw him
improve throughout the season, really
made an impact on that defense, and then
down at the Senior Bowl as well, we got
to see him and we thought he had a great
week.
Go ahead, last one.
Ask it as delicately Every team has
draft misses, but when you draft a
running back in the third round,
some fans were a little like, "Uh-oh."
Um
you know,
and obviously your track record with
mid-round running backs has been maybe
spotty, but
not that you'd get specific with this,
but have you, you know, when when there
is that type of track record, have you
guys gone back and looked at it and say
try to identify, you know, why some of
these guys haven't worked out and Yeah,
we you know, give you more confidence as
you go into We go back every single
year. In January, we'll go we'll go back
and watch the previous year's class
or the previous 2 years classes and
evaluate what went right, what went
wrong, and we watch all the guys around
the league on top of what we do each
week preparing for opponents. So, that
is something that we do a lot of
self-scout of our personnel staff as
well.
Um
and so that that hopefully leads us to
make better picks and better decisions.
Yeah, I would say internally we review
it every year and and talk about it all
throughout the whole process and
um you know, why why we might have hit
on a guy, why we might have missed on a
guy, why maybe the it's still undecided
on a guy. Yeah. And probably the cool
thing about it is,
you know, we we assess it based on our
board and and our standards. So,
we don't really care as much about what
the mocks say, um cuz the mocks don't
necessarily talk about the fourth,
fifth, sixth round players, the the
George Kittles, you know, the Dre
Greenlaws, those type of players that
that we valued in the building, you
know, but there's opportunity day three
especially where we could find players
and then assess where we are with that
part of the process, whether we've done
well and whether we can do better um at
all parts of the board. So, we we're
excited always to kind of go through
that together. It's a help it helps us
grow and it helps us grow as a team.
Yeah, go ahead, Adam. Yeah,
Kyle mentioned earlier how
trying to guess where some of these guys
would have gone,
um
like if it was 20 spots too early, 20
spots too late. Um do you guys even
concern yourself with that in terms of
how other teams might be weighing the
guys that you're interested in?
To a certain degree, but as we as we as
we see every year with us or other
teams, like all it takes is one team.
So, we try to
go through our process and grade the
players, vertically stack the players,
horizontally stack the players, and then
just let the draft come to us and
throughout the off-season process, free
agency,
um all that, we just weigh it all
together and try to
make the best decisions and try to
decide where we think those players are
going to go just based on value, what
we're hearing, team needs, all that
stuff.
All right.
All right, thank you guys. Thank you.
Yeah, thank you.
>> [music]
[music]